Today we are celebrating Sahastrara day.
今天我們慶祝頂輪日。
Perhaps we have not realised what a day it must have been.
或許我們並未意識到這一天的意義非凡。
Without opening the Sahastrara, God Itself was a myth,
在頂輪未被開啟之前，上帝本身只是個神話，
religion itself was a myth, and all talk about Divinity was a myth.
宗教本身也是個神話，所有關於神性的談論都是神話。
People believed in it but it was just a belief.
人們相信它，但那僅僅是一種信仰。
And the science, as it was put forward,
而科學，正如當時所提出的，
was about to obliterate all the value system, all the proof of God Almighty.
正要摧毀所有的價值體系，摧毀一切對全能上帝的證明。
If you see in the history, one after another,
如果你回顧歷史，一個接一個地，
when science established itself,
當科學確立自身地位時，
the people who are so-called in charge of the helm of affairs in religion,
那些被稱為掌管宗教領域的人，
in different religions tried to cope with the findings of science.
在不同宗教中試圖應對科學的發現。
They tried to show that: “All right, if it is said this much – is in the Bible,
他們試圖表明：「好吧，如果聖經裡說了這麼多——
and if it is wrong we should correct it.” Especially Augustine did that.
如果它是錯的，我們就應該糾正它。」特別是奧古斯丁就是這麼做的。
And it started looking as if it’s all a stupidity this,
於是開始有人認為這一切都是愚昧無知，
these scriptures were just mythical.
這些經文只是神話而已。
At least the Koran itself, though, had lots of things which were
至少可蘭經本身，儘管如此，裡面還有很多東西在
describing the biology of today.
描述當代的生物學。
They could not believe that human beings were specially created by God.
他們無法相信人類是由上帝特別創造的。
They thought it was a matter of chance that one after another
他們認為這只是一連串巧合的結果，一個接一個
the animals acquired a situation by which they became human beings.
動物們進化成人類。
Thus all the time Divinity was challenged
因此神性一直受到質疑
and there was no way of giving a proof of whatever
聖經或可蘭經或博伽梵歌或奧義書(古老的梵文經典)
is said in the Bible or in the Koran or in the Gita
或妥拉(希伯來聖經)中所說的一切
or in the Upanishadas or in the Torah.
都無法被證明
Any one of these things could not be proved
因為這些都只是信仰，
because it was still just a faith.
所以無法證明。
Very, very few people got their Realisation
非常、非常少的人得到了他們的自覺
and when they talked,  people did not believe them
當他們談論時，人們不相信他們
and thought that they are just trying to say something
並認為他們只是試圖說些什麼
which they are using to propound their own theories.
以此來支持他們自己的理論。
So the whole thing became a kind of dead science.
所以整件事變成一種死氣沉沉的學問。
There was no science of religion.
宗教本身並無科學可言。
People started thinking that: what’s the use of following these ten commandments
人們開始認為：「遵守這十誡有什麼用處
or these strict rules of life, because by following that you gain nothing.
或遵循這些嚴格的生活規則，因為遵守了你一無所獲。
You lose all the fun of the life.
反而失去了生活中所有的樂趣。
And why think of gaining some punyas also.
何必還要想著積累功德呢？」
And that is how all the time there was a big derailment of human value system.
這就是人類價值體系逐漸偏離正軌的原因。
Also these organised religions, this monolithic organised religions
而且這些有組織的宗教，這種一體化的有組織宗教
started taking to [a] course of gaining power, or gaining money,
開始走上追求權力或金錢的道路，
because they thought that’s the only way you can control people and can go on.
因為他們認為那是唯一能控制人們並維繫自身存在的方法。
They were least bothered as to deliver the goods, whatever have been described in the Bible.
他們根本不在乎是否真正履行了《聖經》中的教義。
Bible of course was tampered [with] very much and has been lot of changes in that.
《聖經》當然被大量篡改過，裡面有許多變動。
And a person like Paul, and Peter, who joined together,
而像保羅與彼得這樣的人，聯手，
tried to spoil most of the Truth.
試圖破壞大多數真理。
Though Koran was not so much touched
雖然《可蘭經》並沒有被如此多地改動。
but still is dealt with more the right side,
但它仍然更多地涉及生殖系統等方面，
with the reproductive system and all those things.
以及所有那些事情有關。
And so many things are still ambiguous.
所以很多事情仍然模糊不清。
Now simultaneously two things have happened, I don’t know if you are aware of it or not.
現在同時發生了兩件事，我不知道你是否有注意到。
First thing that has happened is that now we have
第一件事是現在我們有了
a new science of microbiology
一種新的微生物學科
in which we have discovered that every cell has got a DNA tape.
我們發現每個細胞都有一捲 DNA 帶。
Every cell has got a program in it.
每個細胞裡都有一個程式。
As we have in a computer a chip, every cell has got
就像電腦裡有晶片一樣，每個細胞都有
a tape in it, in a way, that it is programmed.
某種程度上的一條“磁帶”，表示它被程式化了。
And according to that program a development takes place.
而根據那套程式，便會發生一個發展過程。
Now imagine the intricacy of the whole thing!
現在想像整個事情的錯綜複雜！
So many computers are already programmed
已經有這麼多電腦被程式化
and all these cells have these in them.
而所有這些細胞裡都包含著這些東西。
So a very mysterious sort of a thing has come up
所以出現了一種非常神祕的現象
before the scientists and they cannot explain it.
在科學家面前，他們無法解釋它。
They cannot explain many things but one of them is this.
他們無法解釋很多事，但其中之一就是這個。
Now what Sahaja Yoga has done is that
現在霎哈嘉瑜珈已經證明
it has proved that it is the Will of God,
所有一切的運作都源自於神的旨意，
it is the desire of God, the Will of God,
那是神的願望，神的意志，
which is doing all the work.
這一點已被證實。
And it has been proved.
而且這已被證明。
All these Chaitanya, Adi Shakti, is nothing but the Will of God.
所有這些生命能量（Chaitanya）、太初之母（Adi Shakti），無非就是神的旨意，
And Will of God is the One
而上帝的旨意是唯一的
is working out everything very harmoniously.
正在非常和諧地運作著一切。
I don’t know if some of you must have read my book,
我不知道你們當中是否有人讀過我的書，
first book, where I have described how this Earth was created.
第一本書《太初之母之書》（Book of Adi Shakti)，我在裡面描述了這個地球是如何被創造的。
There was a bang, but it was very harmonious,
曾經有一次大爆炸，但那是非常和諧的，
and how it developed is through the Will of God.
地球的演化完全是出於神的旨意。
So everything was done in a way that God’s will was working it out.
所以，一切都按照神的旨意運作的方式進行。
Now the Will of God you are feeling it, on your finger tips.
現在你正感受得到神的旨意，就在你的指尖上。
After Realisation, now, you have discovered the the absolute science,
自覺之後，現在你已經發現了那絕對的科學，
which is the Will of God, which is an absolute science.
那就是上帝的旨意，那是一門絕對的科學。
You people know that we have cured people through Sahaja Yoga.
你們知道我們曾透過霎哈嘉瑜珈治癒過人。
You also know giving bandhan, and all that, things work out.
你們也知道般單等那些做法是有用的。
So many things work out automatically
很多事情會自然而然地解決
after Realisation that people don’t want to believe.
而人們卻不願意相信。
In the beginning people would not believe
一開始人們不會相信
when the scientists told them something, but now it is, you can see,
當科學家告訴他們某件事時，但現在你可以看到，
the science is always in the flux, all the time changing.
科學總是在不斷變化
One theory is again challenged.
一個理論被質疑。
Another theory’s again challenged.
另一個理論又一次受到挑戰。
But Sahaja Yoga has exposed you to that Great Truth of science
但霎哈嘉瑜珈已讓你接觸到那個無法被挑戰、完全存在的偉大神理
which cannot be challenged, which is all there.
那就是一切原本皆在。
So anybody who comes out with any new proposal
因此，任何人提出任何新的主張
about defaming God, or saying that there is no God,
關於誹謗上帝，或說沒有上帝，
we can prove, not [only] that there is God,
我們可以證明，不僅僅是上帝存在，
but that everything, the creation of this Earth,
而且一切，這個地球的創造，
the creation of human beings and everything was done
人類與萬物的創造，都是
harmoniously by the Will of God.
由上帝的旨意和諧地完成的。
If Will of God has done everything,
如果這是上帝的旨意已經做成了一切，
the human beings should not take any credit
那麼人類就不應該為發現一些由上帝所創造的事物而沾沾自喜。
for discovering some things which were created by God.
假設這塊地毯是某人做的，
Supposing this carpet is made by somebody
而我們開始去發現所有的顏色，
and we start discovering all the colours, what is so great?
這有什麼了不起的呢？
It is all there. You cannot create.
一切本都在那裡。不是你創造的。
So it is not the creation part of it [which is] so much important
因此，並不是那個創造的部分本身有那麼重要
but the fashioning of this world, whole thing was done by the Will of God.
而是這個世界的塑造，整件事是由神的意志完成的。
Now if the Will of God is so important,  it has to be proved.
現在如果上帝的意志如此重要，就必須被證明。
And now through Sahaja Yoga, after the breaking of the Sahastrara,
而現在通過霎哈嘉瑜伽，在頂輪被打開之後，
you have now, for the first time, felt the Will of God,
你現在第一次感受到神的旨意，
which is such an important thing,
這是多麼重要的一件事，
but for us it is come to us so Sahaj that we don’t understand.
但對我們來說，它來得如此自然而然，以致我們無法理解。
We just give the bandhan and the things work out and
我們只是給般單，事情就順利解決了，並且
we feel that the things have worked out,
我們感覺事情已經水到渠成，
so it is bandhan which has worked out, and
所以是般單起了作用，而且
we have managed everything. It’s not so.
我們已經處理好一切。事情並非如此簡單。
It’s much more than that.
這遠不止於此。
We have now become part and parcel of that Big Computer of that Will of God.
我們現在已成為那個上帝意志那大型電腦的一部分與一環。
We have become the medium, or we can say the channels, of that Will of God.
我們已成為那意志的媒介，或者可以說，是那意志的管道。
We are connected with that Will of God which created all this Universe.
我們與創造這整個宇宙的神之旨意相連。
So everything we can manage
所以一切我們都能處理
because we have got the Absolute Science in our hand.
因為我們手中掌握著絕對科學。
The Absolute Science which will work out the betterment of the whole world.
這絕對科學將促成整個世界的改善。
We can prove it to the scientist that there is a Will of God
我們可以向科學家證明，確有神之旨意
which has done all this creation.
祂完成了這一切的創造。
Even evolutionary process is the Will of God.
即便是演化的過程，也是上帝的旨意。
Without His Will nothing could have happened.
沒有祂的旨意，什麼都不會發生。
So many people used to say that – not even a blade of grass moves without the Will of God.
很多人常說——即便是一片草葉，沒有上帝的旨意也不會動。
Which is a very true thing.
這句話非常真實。
And you have seen now that – the Will of God we have got as our own power.
而你現在已經看到——上帝的意志已成為我們自己的力量。
We can use it. So how important it is to be a sahaja yogi.
我們可以運用它。所以成為一個霎哈嘉瑜伽士是多麼重要。
Perhaps we don’t realise how important it is to be a sahaja yogi.
也許我們還沒有意識到成為霎哈嘉瑜伽士是多麼重要。
Sahaja Yoga is not only for saying “Mother, I am full of joy,
霎哈嘉瑜伽並不只是為了說「母親，我充滿了喜悅，
I am enjoying myself. I got purified.
我很享受。我已經得到了淨化。
Everything is fine“. But for what?
「一切都很好」。但為了什麼？
Why did you get all these blessings?
你為什麼會得到這些祝福？
Why you have been cleansed? So that this knowledge of the Will of God should be apparent in you.
你為什麼被潔淨？是為了要將神旨意的這份知識在你裡面顯明出來。
Not only that – should be a part and parcel of you.
不僅如此──要成為你的一部分，成為你的一切。
So we have to raise our level, we have to come up.
所以我們必須提升我們的層次，我們必須進步。
For mediocre and ordinary people it is really useless to give them Sahaja Yoga
對於平庸和普通的人來說，傳授霎哈嘉瑜珈真的沒什麼用處
because they are good for nothing.
因為他們一無是處。
They are not going to help us in any way
他們幫不了我們任何忙，
because what is needed is now, today that,
因為現在所需要的是，今天我們應該有
we should have people who can really manifest and reflect the Will of God.
能真正展現並反映上帝旨意的人。
And for that, you can understand, we have to have very strong people
為此，你可以理解，我們必須擁有非常堅強的人
because this Will has created the whole Universe, the Cosmos,
因為這個意志創造了整個宇宙，諸天，
this Mother Earth. Everything is created by this Will of God.
這個地球。萬物皆由這上帝的意志所創造。
So now we are exposed to a new dimension
所以現在我們進入在一個新的維度之中
and that dimension is that we are the ones
而那個維度就是我們就是那些人
who are channels of that Will of God.
是上帝旨意的管道。
So then what is our duty and what should we do about it?
那麼我們的責任是什麼，我們該怎麼做呢？
As a result of Sahastrara being opened out,
由於頂輪被打開，
one thing: the illusions have vanished.
一件事：幻象消失了。
What you call [in] Sanskrit is bhranti.
你在梵語中稱之為 bhranti。
Illusions have vanished.
幻覺已消失。
You should have no illusion as to the existence of God Almighty,
你不應對全能的上帝的存在懷有任何幻象，
the power of his Will and the truth about Sahaja Yoga.
祂旨意的力量以及關於霎哈嘉瑜伽的真相。
You should have no doubts at all, minimum of minimum should be like that.
你一點也不該有疑惑，至少至少應該是這樣。
But while using this Power you should be aware
但在使用這股力量時你應該保持警覺
that this Power is given to you because you are capable of handling it.
這個力量之所以賦予你，是因為你有能力駕馭它。
This is the Highest Power you could think of.
這是你能想到的至高無上的力量。
Take any governor, take any minister, anyone, they can be removed tomorrow.
拿任何一位州長、任何一位部長，或任何人來說，他們明天都可能被免職。
They can become corrupt.
他們可能會變得腐敗。
They can become absolutely devoid of any knowledge of their own powers.
他們可能會完全喪失對自己權力的認知。
There are many people who just get elected without knowing what they have to do.
有很多人當選了，卻不知道自己該做什麼。
So this is not just a conversion of people,
霎哈嘉瑜伽不僅僅是轉變人們，
it’s not only even transformation,
甚至不只是轉化，
but it is a new fashioning of a new human being
而是一種重新塑造全新的人類的過程，
which has come forward and which is capable of carrying the Will of God further.
這種人類已經出現，並且有能力把上帝的旨意推進得更遠。
So as a result of your Realisation, what you have got?
那麼，因為你的自覺，你得到了什麼？
The first thing that has happened is that your illusions have gone.
首先發生的事是你的幻覺消失了。
You should have no illusions about God Almighty, His Will
你不該對全能的上帝、祂的旨意抱有任何幻象
and that He is omnipotent, omnipresent and omniscient.
並且祂是全能、無所不在且無所不知的。
All His omnipotence has done this work,
祂的全能完成了這項工作，
and as a collective consciousness  you should also know that
作為一個集體意識，你也應該知道
you are also omnipotent, omnipresent and omniscient.
你們本身也全能、無所不在並且無所不知。
Omniscient is the thing, that He sees everything, knows everything.
「無所不知」是指祂看見一切、知道一切。
Part of it, that Power, is also within you.
那力量的一部分也存在於你之中。
So to prove His omnipresence you have to all the time be aware
所以為了證明祂的無所不在，你必須時時保持覺知
that you are sahaja yogis. When I find, even now,
你們是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。即使現在我仍發現，
sahaja yogis struggling about their wives, their children,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士在為他們的妻子、孩子而苦惱，
their house, their jobs,
他們的房子、他們的工作，
I start wondering what is their level now?
我就會開始思考，他們現在的程度自哪裡？
Where are they? When are they going to take up the role of what they have got?
他們在哪裡？他們何時會承擔起所擁有的使命？
So the Omnipotent God who is everywhere,
所以那位無所不在的全能神，
who has done all this, the Will of God that has worked it out,
祂完成了這一切，這是上帝旨意的實現，
has to work through you people and you have to be
必須透過你們來運行，而你們必須
very strong, very sensible, very wise, also very effective people.
非常堅定、非常明理、非常智慧，並且是非常有成效的人。
The more effective you become the more energy you will get.
你們越有成效，就會獲得越多的力量。
But still I feel that the sahaja yogis are more,
但我仍然覺得那麼多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士們更傾向於，
not taking the responsibility of understanding
不去承擔起理解的責任
that they have to represent this God Almighty
他們必須代表這位全能的上帝
who is omnipresent, omniscient,
祂是無所不在、無所不知的，
who knows everything, who sees everything
知道一切、看見一切
and who is potent, means Almighty.
能夠施展大能者，即是全能者。
If you understand that this is what has happened after opening the Sahastrara,
如果你明白這是在打開頂輪之後所發生的現象，
that you have now got the power which has these three qualities in it.
你現在已獲得內含這三種特質的力量。
Say now this big thing has to be supported by a strong pillars,
現在說這麼巨大的事物必須由堅固的支柱來支撐，
but supposing if they are not strong, it will fall down.
但假如它們不夠堅固，就會倒塌。
In the same way such a Great Power which has come to you.
以同樣的方式，這樣一股強大的力量降臨到你們身上。
For that we don’t need very successful people,
因此，我們不需要那些非常成功的人，
we don’t need people who have a big name
我們不需要名聲顯赫的人，
or those who have lots of money,
或腰纏萬貫的人，
what we need [is] people of character,
我們需要的是有品格的人，
people of understanding,  of wisdom and of strength,
有理解力、有智慧、有力量的人，
that “Whatever may come I will stand by it,
「無論發生什麼事，我都會堅守它，
I will take to it, I’ll cope with it, I’ll change myself and improve myself“.
我會接受它，我會應對它，我會改變自己並提升自己。」
So now illusion has been dispelled. I hope you all have got rid of your illusions.
所以現在幻象已被打破。希望你們都已擺脫了自己的幻象。
Also you should have no illusions about yourself.
同時你也不應該對自己抱有任何幻象。
If you have any illusions you should leave Sahaja Yoga.
如果你心存任何幻想，你應該離開霎哈嘉瑜珈。
But know that you are chosen for this purpose by God’s Will,
但要知道你是被上帝的旨意選中的，為了這個目的，
that’s why you are here and you have to take it up, the responsibility
這就是你在這裡的原因，你必須承擔起來，承擔起那份責任
of understanding of this science which is absolute.
去理解這門絕對的科學。
And working it out yourself, for yourself as well as for others.
並且為自己以及為他人親自實踐它。
You have felt My love,
你已經感受到我的愛，
but your love must also be felt, because God is love.
但你的愛也必須被感受到，因為神就是愛。
So your love must be felt by others.
所以你的愛必須被他人感受。
Other must feel that you are compassionate, loving, understanding.
他人必須感受到你的慈悲、愛、和理解。
That’s all the time this Will of God is flowing through you.
每當上帝的旨意透過你流動時，就是如此。
And you have to work it out in such a manner
而你必須以這樣的方式去實踐它
that people should know that you are a saint,
讓人們知道你是個聖人，
that this power is flowing through you.
那股力量正透過你流動。
Then the second thing that has happened to you
然後發生在你身上的第二件事是
is that, not the illusion about God and about yourself,
不是關於上帝與你自己的錯覺，
second thing that has happened – that you have understood the integration,
第二件事發生了──你已經理解了整合，
that in the world there is complete integration which is existing.
在這個世界上，存在著完全的整合。
Normally if you see the children, they have their own natural, innate understanding.
通常如果你看小孩，他們有自己自然、與生俱來的理解。
They know. If you see, normally, a good child
他們知道。如果你觀察，通常一個好孩子
would always like to share his things,
總是願意分享他的東西，
would like to love another child,
想要去愛另一個孩子，
if there’s another little child is there, would like to protect that child –
如果那裡有另一個小孩，就想保護那個孩子——
naturally! It won’t think whether it has black hair or red hair or blue hair.
理所當然！牠不會去想自己是黑髮還是紅髮或藍髮。
Naturally, innately a child feels that way.
天生地，孩子就是有這樣的感覺。
Also if you take another child, supposing, who is a little baby,
另外如果你抱另一個孩子，譬如說，是個小嬰兒，
they know that one should be careful about the privacy of the body.
他們就知道要注意保護身體的隱私。
Children don’t want to be made nude before others.
小孩不願意在別人面前赤裸。
No child likes it. Innately they know.
沒有孩子會喜歡。天生他們就知道。
So all these innate qualities are within you.
所以這些與生俱來的品質都在你們內心。
Children don’t like to steal anything.
小孩不喜歡偷東西。
They don’t know what is stealing is. They have no idea of stealing.
他們不知道什麼是偷竊。他們完全不懂偷竊。
I’ve also seen also children that, if they go to a place which is very beautiful,
我也見過有些小孩子，如果他們去到一個非常漂亮的地方，
in somebody’s house, they will always try to keep the beauty of that place.
在別人的家裡，他們會總是想保持那個地方的美麗。
But if it is already shabby they don’t mind.
但如果那地方已經破舊，他們就不在意。
So innately all these qualities are there.
所以這些品質都是與生俱來的。
I think the countries which are supposed to be underdeveloped have so many of these
我認為那些被認為是開發中或未開發的國家，在它們之中有許多這樣的
qualities within them, which are innately built within us.
特質，是根植於我們內在的。
Innocence is innately built.
純真是與生俱來的。
So the Will of God built up,
所以上帝的旨意首先所建立的，
first and foremost thing, was innocence, the auspiciousness.
首要之事，就是純真、吉祥。
The first thing He did was to create Shri Ganesha,
祂做的第一件事就是創造格泥沙，
or I would say, She, because the Will of God is Adi Shakti.
或者我會說，是她，因為上帝的旨意是太初之母。
And all this was created first of all to make the whole world very beautiful.
而且這一切最初創造的目的，是為了讓整個世界變得非常美麗。
All these innate qualities were also placed within you.
所有這些與生俱來的特質也被放在你體內。
All those Deities were placed within you.
所有那些諸神也被置於你體內。
[They] were specially made, human beings,
他們是特別被造的人類，
that they should become saintly people,
使他們成為聖潔的人，
that they should have their saintly, innate sense.
使他們擁有那聖潔的天賦感覺。
But it happened in the countries which developed,
但在那些已開發國家裡發生了這種情況，
that our brain was bombarded by all kinds of television, all kind of things,
我們的大腦被各種電視、各種事物轟炸，
and we became very, we can say, we became very vulnerable.
而我們變得非常、可以說，我們變得非常脆弱。
We started getting into the ideas of others.
我們開始接受他人的觀念。
Anybody who is dominating could dominate us.
任何有支配力的人都能支配我們。
It’s not only Hitler who dominated people.
不只是希特勒能支配人。
We also see today how much we are dominated, if you really detach yourself from this world.
如果你真的能從這個世界抽離出來，今天我們也能看到自己被支配的程度有多深。
For example fashions. Certain things that come up, people cannot give up at any cost.
比如說時尚。有些突然流行起來的東西，無論如何人們都捨不得放棄。
They cannot take to something that is sensible because it’s a fashion.
他們不能接受一些合乎理性的東西，因為那不符合時尚。
For example nowadays there’s a fashion, say to have such a small skirt.
舉例來說，現在有一種時尚，比方說穿這麼短的裙子。
You can’t get a long skirt anywhere.
哪裡都買不到長裙了。
Everybody has to wear that kind of a skirt
每個人都一定要穿那種裙子。
otherwise you are not ‘in’,  you are not in the madhouse!
否則你就不是「裡面」的人，你就不在瘋人院裡！
Now this kind of thing is bombarded on us morning till evening
現在這種東西從早到晚都轟炸我們
so, first of all, we become slaves of these entrepreneurs.
所以，首先，我們就成了這些企業家的奴隸。
Whatever they give us now, I was told that in Belgium you cannot get anything fresh.
他們現在給我們的任何東西，我被告知在比利時你什麼新鮮的東西都買不到。
You have to take everything from the supermarket, which is all tinned.
你得從超市拿一切，都是罐頭貨。
Gradually what is happening to us – we are getting absolutely artificial.
漸漸地我們身上發生的事──我們變得完全人工化。
The food is artificial, the dress is artificial,
食物是人工的，衣著是人工的，
our whole attitude becomes artificial
我們整個態度也變得人工
because we are so much bombarded by advertisement,
因為我們被廣告如此轟炸，
by all kinds of outside influences
被各種外在影響所左右
that we just get lost
我們就會迷失方向
and we forget what is our innate sense
然後忘記我們與生俱來的感知
which is being dominated by all these modern things.
卻被這些現代事物所主導。
So adding up to the science also
因此，除了科學的累積之外
there is  a big progress in another direction,  that we can call,
在另一個方向也有巨大的進展，我們可以稱之為，
the money became very important.
錢變得非常重要。
Once money becomes important,
一旦錢變得重要，
then all your entrepreneurs become important,
那麼你所有的企業家就變得重要，
because they know how to make money and befool you all the time.
因為他們知道如何賺錢並且時常愚弄你們。
Today you have this thing, tomorrow you have that thing.
今天你有這個東西，明天你有那個東西。
Today you change this and have this thing.
今天你改變了這個，並擁有了這個東西。
But those people who are innately built, they do not change!
但那些與生俱來就是這樣的人，他們不會改變！
They have their dresses of the same type, they do not change.
他們穿著同一類型的衣服，他們不改變。
On the contrary they find it very difficult to get out of
相反地，他們覺得很難擺脫
their traditional achievements and they don’t want to change themselves.
他們的傳統成就，而且他們不想改變自己。
So for sahaja yogis it is important to see and watch
所以對於霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說，重要的是看清並觀察
if they are getting this slavery from the entrepreneurs in modern times.
他們是否在現代從企業家那裡獲得了這種奴役。
Then, the thoughts. So many books we read, which gives you thoughts,
然後，是那些想法。我們讀了那麼多書，這些書給你帶來了各種想法，
which are some mad rambling, I would say, of some madman, like Freud.
有些我會說是瘋狂的胡言亂語，像那個瘋子佛洛伊德的言論。
How could Freud influence the West?
佛洛伊德怎麼影響了西方世界？
Because you have lost your innate sense and you accepted.
因為你失去了與生俱來的感知，所以你接受了。
You accepted that and that’s how Freud became your, sort of a, Jesus Christ.
你接受了那一套，這就是佛洛伊德如何成為你的某種耶穌基督。
He became the most important thing.
他成了最重要的東西。
Sex became the most important thing. I mean it’s so simple.
性成了最重要的事。我是說這真是太簡單了。
With little common sense you can understand
有點常識你就能理解
that, at every moment, we are put into this kind of a
那麼，在每一個時刻，我們都被這種由少數幾個
of a domination by these few
專橫的人所施加的支配所置入，
domineering people who have certain ideas, and they put forward.
他們有某些想法，並且提出來。
Anybody puts any idea. For example, Sade (the Marquis de Sade) or Sartre or anyone.
任何人都可以提出任何想法。例如，薩德（薩德侯爵））、薩特或任何人。
That idea starts becoming “Oh he said it“. Who is he?
那個想法便開始變成「哦，他說了」。他是誰？
What is his life? Just see for yourself what sort of a man he is.
他的生活是什麼樣子？你自己看看他是個怎樣的人。
With little common sense. But with your will that you have now,
幾乎沒有常識。但有你現在所擁有的意志，
Will of God, which has fashioned the whole world, which has fashioned you.
那是上帝的意志，造就了整個世界，也造就了你。
Every cell within you has been fashioned by God Almighty
你體內的每一個細胞都是由全能的上帝造就的
and what you are doing is to play into the hands of these entrepreneurs.
而你現在所做的，卻正中這些商人的下懷。
They have realised that these vulnerable people are very good for
他們已經察覺到，這些弱勢者非常適合
having as their disciples,  I should say, to make money, to befool them.
成為他們的門徒，我應該說，用來賺錢、愚弄他們。
Now on this side, you have such a Great Power,
而在這一方面，你擁有如此巨大的力量，
you are chosen for a, such a great thing,
你被選中承擔如此重大的事，
and on the other side you have this kind of slavery.
而在另一邊，卻有這種奴役。
So try to understand that your innate qualities were lost.
所以試著理解，你與生俱來的本質曾經失落。
But luckily, by the Kundalini awakening and by the breaking of the Sahastrara,
但幸運的是，藉由昆達里尼的覺醒與頂輪的打開，
all these innate qualities which looked like lost:
所有這些看似失落的與生俱來的特質：
like your innocence, like your creativity,
像你的純真，像你的創造力，
like your religion within, like your compassion
像你內在的信仰，像你的慈悲
and love for the humanity , like your power of judgment, wisdom.
以及對人類的愛，還有像你那樣的判斷力、智慧。
All these great qualities which we thought were lost were nothing
我們以為已經失去的所有這些偉大品質其實
but they were in a dormant state.
只是處於休眠狀態。
They all got awakened one by one.
它們一一被喚醒了。
I don’t have to tell you “Don’t drink this!
我不用告訴你「別喝這個！」
Don’t eat this! Don’t do that!”.
別吃這個！別做那個！
You yourself realise that this is wrong.
你自己也意識到這是錯的。
You yourself know what is good for you.
你自己也知道什麼對你有益。
And still if you want to do wrong you can go ahead.
但即便如此，如果你想做錯事，你仍可以繼續去做。
But already there is a light within you to see for yourself
不過你內心已有一道光，讓你能夠自己看清。
what is good and what is bad.
什麼是好的，什麼是壞的。
It has come because of this Sahastrara being opened out
這是因為頂輪被打開了
to this – a new dimension of new knowledge.
通向這個──新的知識維度。
And this is not new, it is all innately built within you.
而這並非新事物，這一切本就先天內建於你之中。
Now all those innate qualities are manifesting and you are enjoying them.
現在那些先天的品質正在顯現，你也在享受它們。
So now you have to get out of your petty ideas and petty things.
所以現在你必須擺脫那些狹隘的想法和瑣碎的事物。
People are reporting to Me something very funny –
有人在向我報告一些非常好笑的事情──
I can’t believe sahaja yogis can do like that –
我真的無法相信霎哈嘉瑜珈士會這樣做──
that they run away with the plates that I have bought,
他們竟然把我買的盤子拿走，
or they run away with the cups, they throw things here and there,
或者他們拿走杯子，到處扔東西，
all over the places they are throwing things.
到處都有人在亂丟東西。
How can you behave like this?
你怎麼可以這樣行為？
I mean this is so stupid and so insipid.
我是說，這太愚蠢也太乏味了。
If you do not have a proper discipline of life yourself,
如果你自己沒有正確的生活紀律，
you cannot carry the Will of God, you cannot.
你就無法承載上帝的旨意，你做不到。
But I’m not going to tell you “Do this or do that!”
但我不會告訴你「做這個或做那個！」
I respect your freedom
我尊重你的自由
and I just want that your own Kundalini should awaken that wisdom in you,
我只是希望你的昆達里尼能覺醒你內在的智慧，
that greatness in you, that glory in you
你內在的偉大，那份榮耀
and you start understanding what is our innate quality.
讓你開始理解什麼是我們與生俱來的本質。
So it will purify you.
所以它會淨化你。
Once you are purified completely, like
一旦你完全被淨化，就像
you see, if you have some gold which is not pure
你看，如果你有一些不純的金子
you put it in the fire,  the gold is separated.
你把它放進火裡，金子就會被分離。
In the same way, the fire of Kundalini cleanses you completely,
以同樣的方式，昆達里尼之火會徹底清洗你，
makes you absolutely clean,
使你完全清淨，
and you start seeing your own glory, your own nature, your own greatness.
你開始看到自己的光輝、自己的本性、自己的偉大。
So the integration part comes to you easily. You start integrating.
所以整合的部分對你來說變得容易。你開始整合。
First of all, we used to have sahaja yogis, say from,
首先，我們以前有一些霎哈嘉瑜珈士，比如來自，
some from England, some from Spain, some from here.
有些來自英國、有些來自西班牙、有些來自這裡。
They would always have different groups, they would never sit together.
他們總是分成不同的群體，從不會坐在一起。
You could make out this is English sitting here,
你可以看得出這裡坐著的是英國人，
they are sitting here, they are sitting here, and they would form a group.
他們坐在這裡，他們坐在這裡，他們會成一群。
But now it’s not so. Now I find they all are becoming integrated.
但現在不是這樣了。現在我發現他們都在逐漸融合。
The integration of human beings is the most important thing for Sahaja Yoga.
人類的整合是霎哈嘉瑜珈最重要的事。
That comes by understanding, not by your intelligence,
這來自於理解，不是來自你的智力，
but by innate understanding that – all human beings are made by God,
而是靠內在的理解──所有人類都是由上帝造的，
by His will, and we have no right to despise anyone.
依祂的旨意，我們沒有權利蔑視任何人。
The second integration that has come within you is that all religions,
你內在出現的第二種整合是，所有宗教，
all religions, are born on the same tree of spiritual life.
所有宗教，都生於同一棵靈性生活之樹。
That all religions are to be worshipped, all incarnations,
所有宗教皆應被崇敬，所有降世神祈，
all prophets, all scriptures are to be worshipped.
所有先知、所有經文皆應被崇敬。
There are defects, there are problems with those scriptures which can be corrected.
那些經文中有缺失、有問題，是可以被修正的。
So gradually you start entering into the subtler side of Divinity,
因此，你會逐漸進入神性的更精微面向，
to understand that all these people have worked hard
去理解這些人都曾努力奮鬥
to create, today, the atmosphere for Sahaja Yoga,
要在今天，為霎哈嘉瑜伽創造那種氛圍，
and no religion is to be despised, and no religion is to be attacked,
沒有任何宗教應被輕視，也沒有任何宗教應被攻擊，
which is a very, very, absolutely a unreal thing
這是一件非常、非常、絕對不真實的事情
and you are working out a very unreal theory
而人類正在推行一個非常不真實的理論
which doesn’t exist in the Divine plan.
這在神聖的計畫中並不存在。
So this is how we finish all fundamentalism.
所以這就是我們終結所有原教旨主義的方式。
Fundamentalists are the ones who believed that
狂熱原教旨主義者就是那些相信
this is written in this book, this is written in this book,
這個寫在這本書上，這個寫在這本書上，
and that we, because we read this book, we are something better.
然後因為我們讀了這本書，我們就比別人更優越。
Anybody can read any book, what is so great?
任何人都可以讀任何書，有什麼了不起的？
Same, I would say, in Sahaja Yoga people should not become fundamentalist.
我會說，霎哈嘉瑜伽士也不應該變得原教旨主義。
Be very careful!
要非常小心！
Because that’s what you are – born like that, I mean,
因為你就是那樣——天生如此，我的意思是，
I don’t know, it’s not your innate quality  but
我不知道，這不是你的與生俱來的特質，但
the way you are made that way, you have fashioned yourself that way,
你就是被塑造成那樣，你已經把自己塑造成那樣，
that you start also making Sahaja Yoga sometimes a fundamental.
以至於你有時也會把霎哈嘉瑜伽變成狂熱原教旨主義
“Mother said so.”
「母親是這麼說的。」
Do not use Me anywhere!
任何地方都不要使用「我」！
“Mother said so!” Is a way you want to dominate others.
「母親是這麼說的！」這是一種你想支配他人的方式。
You yourself say because now you have a right, you have an individuality in Sahaja Yoga.
你自己說，因為現在你在霎哈嘉瑜伽中有了權利，你有了個體性。
You can say what you have to say yourself,
你可以自己說你想說的話，
but don’t say that “Mother has said it!”
但不要說「母親說過了！」
Because anybody can start it, like that: “Christ said it!”.
因為任何人都能那樣開始說：「基督說過！」
A clergyman or, a say, pope can stand up on his
一位神職人員，或者說，例如教宗，可以站在他自己的
own platform  and say that Christ has said it.
講壇上說基督曾經這麼說過。
They can just arbitrarily use all these things.
他們可以任意使用這些東西。
So nobody has business to use Me arbitrarily.
所以沒有人有權任意使用我。
Whatever you have to say you say yourself.
你要說甚麼就自己說。
But don’t ever quote Me as that: “Mother has said it,”
但絕不要把我引用成那樣：「母親說過，」
or, “In this book such and such is written, so this is the line, that is important.
或是：「在這本書裡寫了這個那個，所以這是要走的路，那個是重要的。」
” You are not bound by any line, by whatever I say.
「你不受任何界限所束縛，不論我說什麼。
It is you who has to stand up and see for yourself what you have to say,
而是你自己必須站起來，親自看清你必須說的話，
because you have to use now your will
因為你現在必須運用你的意志
and for that you have to develop yourself to have Pure Will, the Pure Desire of God Almighty.
為此你必須修為自己，以擁有純粹的意志，擁有全能神的純粹渴望。
The integration not only outward, but inward.
不僅是外在的整合，更是內在的整合。」
Like first of all, whatever we did, our mind used to say one thing,
首先，不管我們做了什麼，我們的心智以前會說一件事，
our heart used to say another thing, our brain used to say another thing.
我們的內心會說另一件事，我們的大腦會說第三件事。
Now what has happened that all these 3 things have become one.
但現在發生的是，這三者已經合為一體。
So, whatever your brain says is absolutely acceptable to your heart,
所以，無論你的大腦說什麼，你的內心都完全接受，
absolutely acceptable to your attention.
完全為你的注意力所接受。
So you yourself, you have become now integrated.
所以你自己，現在已經融入了。
Many people write “Mother I want to do it, but I can’t do it,”
很多人會寫「母親我想去做，但我做不到，」
“Mother it was my desire to do it, but I can’t do it.” Not now.
「母親我本來渴望去做，但我做不到。」現在不會了。
Now you are completely integrated and you can easily do the whole thing very well.
現在你已經完全融入了，可以很輕鬆地把整件事做好。
If you want to examine yourself, you should try to find out “Am I integrated or not?
如果你想檢視自己，應該試著找出「我是否已經融入了？」
Whatever I’m doing, am I doing with my full heart or not,
無論我在做什麼，我是全心全意去做，還是沒有？
with my full attention or not?”
是以全部注意力去做，還是沒有？」
I’ve seen that you do with full heart and full intelligence
我見過有人是以全心與全意去做，
but full attention is not there.
但卻缺乏完全的專注。
Still the attention, which is the first thing that was enlightened, is not fully used.
然而，注意力——那最初被啟發的東西，仍未被充分運用。
So the whole attention should be absolutely there,
所以整個注意力應該完全在那裡，
that, “I have to do this thing with full attention.”
也就是，「我必須用全心的注意力做這件事。」
Otherwise, the integration is not complete, integration is partial.
否則，整合就不完整，整合是部分的。
So these three things have to be completely integrated.
所以這三樣東西必須完全整合。
So the integration of all the chakras comes in.
於是所有輪穴的整合就會發生。
Like whatever you do, has to be auspicious.
無論你做什麼，都得是吉祥的。
Whatever you do has to be with full attention.
無論你做什麼，都得全神貫注。
Whatever you do has to be absolutely religious.
無論你做什麼，都得非常虔誠。
So like that, all these centres are being absolutely,
所以像這樣，所有這些能量中心都被徹底地，
one integrated power that you have.
成為你擁有的一股整合的力量。
So the whole life should be integrated.
所以整個人生都應該被整合起來。
Now, say somebody’s husband is not that level
現在，比方說某人的丈夫沒有達到那種境界
or somebody’s wife is not of that level,  you shouldn’t bother.
或者某人的妻子沒有達到那種境界，你就不應該為此煩惱。
You should just bother about yourself. Don’t expect anything from anybody else.
你應該只專注於自身。不要對別人抱任何期望。
It is your duty which is important. You have to fulfill your duty
重要的是你的責任。你必須完成你的責任。
and you have to work it out yourself.
你必須靠自己去實現它。
Unless and until you understand that it is your individual being
除非並且直到你明白是你這個個體存在
which has achieved it, and it’s the individual being which has to realise it,
達到了它，並且是這個個體存在必須去體認它，
is the individual being that has to become one, integrated with the rest of them.
是這個個體存在必須成為一個，與其它部分整合為一體。
If you start putting things, like many a times I’ve seen
如果你開始把事情放在別處，就像我多次見到的那樣
[that] if I say something people start thinking
如果我說了什麼，人們開始就會去揣測
that I am saying for somebody else, they never take it for themselves.
我是在說別人，他們從不把它當成對自己說的。
So,not we have to see what is my gain: “I’ve got financial gain" say
所以，我們必須看看我的得益是什麼：「我有了財務上的收益」說
“I’ve got physical gains, I’ve got mental gains, I’ve got joy, happiness”
「我有了身體上的收穫，我有了心理上的收益，我有了喜悅、幸福」
that’s not the only thing.
那並不是唯一的事。
That should not be the only criteria.
那不應該是唯一的標準。
But what you should have is the understanding
但你應該擁有的是對自己個性的理解
of your own personality which is being specially fashioned
那個個性正被特別塑造
[through] many, many lives for you to come in this life to get your Realisation,
[透過]許多許多輪迴，為了讓你今生獲得自覺，
to do the further work of Will of God.
去完成上帝旨意的進一步工作。
Every moment when you see a miracle taking place, you do realise
每當你看到奇蹟發生的每一刻，你都會意識到
that it’s all done by Paramchaitanya.
這一切都是至高無上生命能量流（Paramchaitanya）所為，
But what is Paramchaitanya – is the will of Adi Shakti.
那麼至高無上生命能量流是什麼——是太初之母的意志。
And what is Adi Shakti – is the Will of God.
而太初之母是什麼——是上帝的旨意。
So, is all, whatever is done, is all ‘fixed entities’, we can call them,
那麼，一切，無論做了什麼，都是「固定的實體」，我們可以這麼稱呼，
or these vibrations are like, we can say, DNA tapes.
或者這些生命能量就像，我們可以說，是 DNA 磁帶。
They all know how they have to fashion you.
他們都知道該如何塑造你。
See, today it’s very sunny.
看，今天陽光很明媚。
Everybody is surprised how can they have.
每個人都驚訝於天氣如此晴朗。
So many things happen like this.
有這麼多事情就是這樣發生。
The other day, we had havan, it was absolutely sunny.
前幾天我們做了火祭，天氣非常晴朗。
So the whole Cosmos is working for you.
所以整個宇宙都在為你運作。
You are on the stage now and you have to see to it,
你現在在舞台上，必須把握機會。
but if you don’t have faith in yourself,
但如果你對自己沒有信心，
if you are not confident as to what you are, how can you help?
如果你對自己缺乏自信，你又如何能有所作為？
How can you work out yourself and work out all the problems of the world,
你又如何能完善自身，並解決世界上所有那些難題，
which are created only by human beings?
這些問題完全是由人類自身所造成的？
So we have to absolutely overthrow all these dominations on us.
所以我們必須徹底推翻所有對我們的這些支配。
First from science. We can prove everything that Sahaja Yoga,
首先從科學開始。
whatever it has said about science, has been proved.
我們可以證明霎哈嘉瑜珈所說的任何關於科學的事，都已被證實。
So, we can throw science which is just always,
所以，我們可以拋開那些總是，
all the time, in the flux, it’s changing all the time.
一直在變動的科學，它不斷在流動，時時改變。
Then the so-called religions that we have.
然後是我們所謂的宗教。
So-called religions because people who have been Catholics,
之所以稱為「所謂」，是因為曾經是天主教徒的人，
who have been Protestants, who have been Hindus or Muslims, or this and that,
曾經是新教徒、或是印度教徒、或是回教徒，或這個那個的人，
they all have got that thing on their heads.
他們頭上都有那個東西。
And this has to be thrown away.
而這些必須被丟掉。
We have to become a new personality.
我們必須變成一個全新的人。
After Realisation, as I said, you become like a lotuses is from the mud.
如我所說，自覺之後，你就像從泥裡長出的蓮花。
So now you have become lotuses and the lotuses
所以現在你已經成為了蓮花，而蓮花
have to throw away all this dead mud,
必須把這些枯死的泥土全部丟掉，
otherwise fragrance won’t be there.
否則就不會芬芳。
That, one has to achieve:
那個，必須要達到的是：
is to throw away all these shackles which are, which are killing you,
就是掙脫所有束縛你們的枷鎖，那些束縛正把你殺死，
which are of no use, but a burden.
它們沒有任何用處，只是負擔。
And beautiful lotuses as you are
而且像你這樣美麗的蓮花
you have to understand that the whole fashioning has been done so carefully,
你必須明白，整個塑造過程是如此小心謹慎地完成的，
with such sweetness, with such delicacy.
帶著如此的溫柔，帶著如此的纖細。
So first of all we must have respect for ourselves,
所以首先我們必須對自己抱持尊重，
we must have affection and love for others
我們必須對他人懷有關愛與慈愛
and we must have respect, means we must have discipline.
而且我們必須有尊重，意思是我們必須有紀律。
We have to have the discipline
我們必須要有紀律
because if you respect yourself you’ll definitely discipline yourself
因為如果你尊重自己，你一定會約束自己
and you’ll make it available.
並且你會把它付諸實行。
Now as you can realise, that from My life itself,
現在正如你可以從我的生活本身所體會到的，
that I work very hard, travel a lot, much more than any one of you can do.
我工作非常努力，經常旅行，比你們任何一個人都多得多。
Because I have the will that – I have to bring this world
因為我有這個意志──我必須把這個世界
to that state of enjoyment, to that state of happiness,
帶到那種享受的境界，帶到那種幸福的境界，
to that state of Divinity, where they realise
帶到那種神性的境界，在那裡他們會領悟
what is their glory, what is the glory of their Father.
什麼是他們的榮耀，什麼是天父的榮耀。
So I work very hard and I never even think
所以我努力工作，從未想過
that something will go wrong with Me,
會有什麼事情會發生在我身上，
or “This will happen”,  “What will happen?”
或「會發生這個」、「會怎麼樣？」
I never have bothered you about My family life,
我從未因為我的家庭生活打擾過你，
about My children, about anyone.
或我的孩子，或任何人。
Whatever problems I had, I am dealing with them Myself.
不管我有什麼問題，我都是自己在處理。
But here I get such big, big letters from sahaja yogis,
但在這裡我看到一些霎哈嘉瑜伽士寫了這麼大篇幅的內容，
writing about their daughter, their son, this thing, that thing.
談他們的女兒、他們的兒子、這個那個的事情。
Another thing is attachment to family is the biggest burden on your heads
另一件事是對家庭的執著是你們頭上的最大負擔，
and all the time you are worried about your children,
而且你們整天都在為孩子擔心，
you are worried about this, you are worried about that.
你為這個擔心，為那個擔心。
That’s not your responsibility.
那不是你的責任。
Please try to understand.
請試著理解。
That’s the responsibility of God Almighty.
那是全能上帝的責任。
You can’t do better than Him can you?
你能做得比祂更好嗎？
But when you try to take the responsibility He says “All right, look after!”
但當你試圖承擔責任時，他會說：「好吧，你自己辦吧！」
and the problems start.
然後問題就開始了。
‘Detachment’ is the word one should understand in a proper sense.
「超然」是應當以正確意義理解的詞。
When I ask people why do you throw things here and there, say
當我問人們為什麼把東西亂丟時，他們會說
“We are detached!”- wonderful way!
「我們是超然的！」——多麼奇妙的說法！
And what about your children? You cling on to them.
那你的孩子呢？你抓著他們不放。
What about your own things? You cling on to them.
你自己的東西呢？你抓著它們不放。
For a small little thing, they’ll bother My head.
為了一點小事，他們就會煩擾我。
And, when it belongs to Me or to Sahaja Yoga,
而且，當它屬於我或屬於霎哈嘉瑜珈，
then they’ll have a very nice time with it –
那麼他們就不在乎，
and throw it away,  wherever they feel like.
然後隨手丟掉，想丟哪裡就丟哪裡。
I mean this kind of irresponsibility!
我的意思是說這種不負責任的行為！
How can you call them divine?
你怎麼能稱他們為聖人？
How can they be saintly people?
他們怎麼能是聖潔的人？
Saintly people not only are responsible for themselves, but for everyone.
聖潔的人不僅要對自己負責，還要對所有人負責。
Very slowly, smoothly, sweetly, with great affection,
非常緩慢、平穩、甜美，帶著深厚的情感，
I have brought you to this level.
我已將你帶到了這個境界。
I didn’t ask you to go to Himalayas or stand on your heads
我並沒有要求你去喜馬拉雅山或倒立，
or to donate all your properties to Me. Nothing of the kind.
也沒有要求你把所有財產都捐給我。完全不是那樣。
We have managed it in a very, very beautiful manner.
我們以一種非常非常美好的方式完成了這一切。
Now further, when you have to go further,
現在更進一步，當你必須更進一步時，
then you have to understand that your duties
你必須明白你的責任
are to be fulfilled by you and by nobody else.
要由你去完成，別無他人可代替。
But these duties are done by you,
而這些責任是由你來完成的，
are towards your family, towards your house, towards this, towards that.
針對你的家庭、對你的房子、對這個、對那個。
No duties towards Sahaja Yoga.
對霎哈嘉瑜伽沒有任何義務。
So when you were, before Sahaja Yoga, you were not attached to anyone,
所以當你在接觸霎哈嘉瑜伽之前，你不依附於任何人，
in the sense – you were only attached to yourself, self-centered.
從某種意義上說——你只依附於自己，以自我為中心。
Now you have widened yourself a little more,
現在你稍微拓寬了自己，
that now you are attached to your wife, to your children.
現在你依附於你的妻子、你的孩子。
But that’s just the same.
但那也沒什麼兩樣。
That is also selfish, because they are your children, you think.
這也是自私的，因為你們認為他們是你們的孩子。
They are not your children, they are the children of God.
他們不是你們的孩子，他們是上帝的孩子。
I hope all of you are intelligent enough to understand
我希望你們所有人都夠聰明能理解
your responsibility and work it out.
你們的責任並把它做好。
This is a very important thing that has happened to you
這對你來說是一件非常重要的事
that Sahastrara has opened.
頂輪已經打開。
Now you can prove the existence of God,
現在你可以向全世界證明上帝的存在、
His Will, everything, to the whole world.
祂的旨意、所有一切。
Nobody can challenge Sahaja Yoga.
沒有人可以挑戰霎哈嘉瑜伽。
Those scientist who will challenge can be told.
那些要挑戰的科學家可以告訴他們。
Anybody, whether you’re a scientist, economist, politician, anything,
任何人，無論你是科學家、經濟學家、政治人物，或其他任何身分，
everything can be explained in the light of Sahaja Yoga
一切都可以用霎哈嘉瑜伽之光來解釋
and can be proved that there’s only one politics –that is of God,
並且可以證明只有一種政治──那就是上帝的政治，
one economics – that is of God,
一種經濟──那就是上帝的經濟，
and there is only one religion – that is of God,  is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma.
而且只有一種宗教——那就是屬於上帝的，名為普世純淨法( Vishwa Nirmala Dharma)。
It can be proved,
這是可以被證明的，
there’s nothing to be afraid of or to worry about.
沒有什麼可害怕或擔憂的。
This all can be proved to the scientist and
這一切都可以向科學家證明，
to the other intellectuals and to some few people
向其他知識分子以及少數人證明
if they want to listen to us.
如果他們願意聽我們說話。
If they don’t want to listen to us, forget it.
如果他們不願意聽我們，就算了吧。
Because we are so powerful, why should you worry about them?
既然我們這麼強大，你為何還要擔心他們？
But, if they are willing to listen to us,
但是，如果他們願意聽我們，
then is better that we tell them “Now we have discovered this Great Power”,
那麼最好告訴他們「現在我們已經發現了這種偉大的力量」，
and if it works out,
它真的奏效了，
if this Great Power works out
如果這種偉大的力量奏效了，
then only we can really fashion the whole world in a new way.
那麼只有我們才能真正以一種新的方式塑造整個世界。
I have great hopes from you people,
我對你們寄予厚望，
but the seriousness with which you should take Sahaja Yoga,
但你們對待霎哈嘉瑜伽的態度，
for example even meditation, people don’t do.
例如連冥想這種事，人們都不做。
Simple thing like meditation, you people don’t do,  I can’t understand.
像冥想這麼簡單的事情，你們不做，我無法理解。
How will you grow without meditation?
沒有冥想你們如何成長？
Unless and until you become thoughtlessly aware you cannot grow.
除非並直到你達到無思慮覺知的狀態，你無法成長。
So you have to, you have to at least meditate morning, evening.
所以你必須，你至少要早晚冥想。
There are many people who are not even collective by temperament.
有許多人天性就不喜歡集體生活。
If they are staying in an ashram they just think that ashram life is no good.
如果他們住在靜修中心，就會認為靜修中心的生活不好。
Such people should really get out of Sahaja Yoga,
這樣的人其實應該離開霎哈嘉瑜伽，
because they have not yet understood what this Sahaja Yoga is.
因為他們還不明白這個霎哈嘉瑜伽是什麼。
Without collectivity how will you grow?
沒有集體性，你怎麼會成長？
How will you assemble your power? You see?
你要怎樣集合你的力量？懂嗎？
You know very well that in a sangha, in a group,
你很清楚，在集體裡，在一個團體中，
in combining together only, you can be strong.
只有透過結合在一起，你才能強大。
Is a fact that if you have one stick you can break it,
事實是，如果你只有一根棍子，你可以折斷它，
but if you put many sticks together you cannot break it.
但如果你把許多棍子綁在一起，你就折不斷它。
But there are still people I know who are still not so much in collectivity.
但我仍然認識一些人，他們對於「集體」的概念仍然不太在意。
Shows how poor they are in their understanding of their own Self,
這顯示出他們對真我的理解有多麼貧乏，
and they are telling Me that “Mother,
而他們還對我說：「母親，
we don’t want to stay in the Ashram  now anywhere more.”
我們現在不想再待在這個靜修中心了。」
So they should get out of Sahaja Yoga.
所以他們應該離開霎哈嘉瑜珈。
Without the collectivity, you cannot grow.
沒有集體，你無法成長。
Without the discipline of Sahaja Yoga, you cannot grow.
沒有霎哈嘉瑜珈的紀律，你無法成長。
It’s better to have ten people of good quality than to have thousand useless people.
擁有十個高素質的人，總比擁有一千個無用之人要好。
That’s what is the Will of God.
這就是上帝的旨意。
So now, as you are today here,  so many people,
所以現在，就像今天你們在這裡，這麼多人，
I am really enamoured  to see so many people are there.
我真的很高興看到有這麼多人在這裡。
And we have done so much of our growth
我們已經做了很多成長
and grown out of all those nonsensical things that we were following.
並且擺脫了過去那些我們所追隨的荒謬事物。
But today we have to take a vow
但今天我們必須立下一個誓言
that –  “I’ll now fashion my life according to the Will of God.
那就是「我現在要按著上帝的旨意來塑造我的人生。」
Absolutely. And dedicate myself to that.”
絕對可以。並全心投入於此。」
No family, no other considerations.
沒有家庭，沒有其他考量。
Just forget it! Nothing so important.
忘掉它們吧！沒有什麼那麼重要。
Everything can be looked after by Will of God.
一切都可以交由神的旨意來照管。
So if you just try to follow the Will of God,
所以如果你只是嘗試去遵行神的旨意，
your children will be looked after,
你的孩子會被照顧好，
everything will be looked after, you don’t have to worry for anything.
一切都會被處理妥當，你什麼都不用擔心。
And that works.
而且那是有效的。
Just try to understand that you have problems
只要試著理解，你之所以有這些問題
because you don’t want to give those problems to God,
是因為你不願把那些問題交給上帝，
you want to keep it to themselves, that’s why you have problems.
你想把它留給自己，這就是你有問題的原因。
If you decide that “No,
如果你決定說：「不，
I just want to give these problems to the God’s will,” Finished!
我只是想把這些問題交給上帝的旨意，」就結束了！
Also there are some who want to say that “We are not so capable
也有些人想說：「我們沒那麼能幹
Mother, we can’t do it.” Saying like this also is stupid.
母親，我們做不到。」這樣說也很愚蠢。
You test yourself, you see for yourself.
你檢驗自己，你親眼看見。
So first of all, one has to understand why do we say such a thing?
那麼首先，必須明白我們為何會這麼說？
Maybe that we are very money-oriented,
也許是因為我們非常以金錢為導向，
that we want to have money to ourselves, or something like that.
我們想擁有金錢，或類似的東西。
Or some people are there who talk of business also in Sahaja Yoga.
或是在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，也有人談論生意。
There must be something like a money orientation,
一定有類似於金錢取向的東西，
or some sort of a material attachment
或某種物質上的依附感
that they say that ‘We are not capable, we cannot change.”
讓他們說「我們做不到，我們無法改變。」
The second could be this mamatwa as they call it.
第二個可能就是他們所說的執著。
The attachment to your family, children, this, that.
對家庭、孩子等的執著。
Or, ‘This is mine, this is mine,this is mine.”
或者，「這是我的，這是我的，這是我的。」
This could be the second reason
這可能是第二個原因
that you think that you are not bold enough
讓你覺得自己不夠勇敢
or you are not strong enough to do Sahaja Yoga.
或不夠堅強來修習霎哈嘉瑜珈。
Thirdly could be that you are still playing with your old habits
第三個原因可能是你仍在縈繞於舊習慣。
and that you are enjoying your life without virtues.
而且你正享受著沒有美德的生活。
There can be some reason like that.
可能有某種像那樣的原因。
So just try to locate, “Why am I behaving like this?
所以試著去找出，「為什麼我會這樣行為？
Why am I not getting into the same
為什麼我沒有走上大家都走的那條
beautiful path of my ascent as everybody has got it.”
美麗的上升之路。」
If we introspect, you’ll find out that "There’s something wrong with me
如果我們自我內省，你會發現「我覺得自己做不到，自己有問題。」
that I think I am not capable of doing.”
你有能力做任何事！
You are capable of doing everything!
你只要試試看，並享受它。
You just try this and enjoy it.
所以，現在最重要的事情是你應該成為一個
So, most important thing now [that] remains is that you should become a
你應該成為一個
proper, strong, compassionate vehicle of God’s Will.
合宜、堅強、充滿慈悲的上帝旨意載體。
So. Then, what is most important of course,
所以。那麼，當然最重要的是什麼，
I agree, that you do My puja, because that helps you a lot, no doubt.
我同意，你們進行我的崇拜，因為那確實幫助你們很多，這點無疑。
But other things are not important.
但其他事情並不重要。
So many other things you people tell Me is not of importance.
所以你們告訴我的許多其他事情並不重要。
Main thing is that you should all ascend higher and higher
最重要的是你們都應該不斷提升，越來越高
and compete with each other in getting into higher situation.
並彼此競爭，爭取進入更高的境界。
As it is, I think in such a short time we have achieved a lot, no doubt,
照目前情況，我認為在這麼短的時間內我們已經取得了很多成就，毫無疑問，
but still we have to speed up and work it out.
但我們仍然必須加速並把它完成。
I am sure that this new science, or we can say, the, which is the
我確信這門新科學，或者我們可以說，那個，亦即是
absolute science will one day outshadow
絕對科學終有一日會勝過
the other science, and tell people that: this is what it is.
其他科學，並告訴人們：這就是它的本來面目。
It is in your hands, you work it out.
這在你們手中，由你們去推演。
So today is the day we are celebrate by which
所以今天是我們慶祝的日子，因為
we have opened absolutely a new dimension,
我們已經完全開啟了一個全新的維度，
absolutely a venue of great Divinity,
絕對是一個偉大神性的場所，
of the proofs of Divine.
作為神性證明的一部分。
And this is something so great that we can really finish
這真是如此巨大，以至於我們真的可以結束
all the illusions they have about themselves, about their ego.
他們對自己、對自我所有的幻象。
We can manage them.
我們可以掌控他們。
That power you all have.
你們擁有的那種力量。
May God Bless You.
願上帝保佑你們。